{
  "data": [
    {
      "question": "Fire safety is the set of practices:",
      "choices": ["Intended to reduce the destruction caused by fire", "prevent ignition of an uncontrolled fire", "limit the development and effects of a fire after it starts", "All the above"],
      "answer": "All the above"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is definition of fire",
      "choices": ["A fire is self-sustained oxidation of a fuel that emits heat and light", "A fire is artificial phenomena", "A fire absorbs heat", "A fire is self-sustained reduction of a fuel that emits heat and light"],
      "answer": "A fire is self-sustained oxidation of a fuel that emits heat and light"
    },
    {
      "question": "How many variables affect fire:",
      "choices": ["4", "2", "3", "1"],
      "answer": "3"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the elements of fire tetrahedron?",
      "choices": ["Fuel, oxygen, temperature, chain reaction", "Fuel, carbon dioxide, temperature, chain reaction", "Ash, nitrogen, temperature, chain reaction", "Fuel, oxygen, temperature, displacement reaction"],
      "answer": "Fuel, oxygen, temperature, chain reaction"
    },
    {
      "question": "How many variables are required to sustain fire:",
      "choices": ["5", "4", "3", "2"],
      "answer": "4"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not a product of fire chemical chain reactions?",
      "choices": ["CO", "CO2", "N2", "C"],
      "answer": "N2"
    },
    {
      "question": "How does fire prevention differ from fire protection?",
      "choices": ["fire prevention attempts to eliminate the variables of the fire triangle before a fire occurs", "fire prevention attempts to control the variables of the fire triangle before a fire occurs", "fire prevention enhances the variables of the fire triangle if a fire occurs", "It is the same"],
      "answer": "fire prevention attempts to control the variables of the fire triangle before a fire occurs"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fire prevention strategies include:",
      "choices": ["Using fire extinguishers", "Controlling heat sources", "Oxidise fuels", "None of the above"],
      "answer": "Controlling heat sources"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not a stage of fire?",
      "choices": ["Incident stage", "Smoldering stage", "Free burning stage", "Both b and c"],
      "answer": "Incident stage"
    },
    {
      "question": "_________ fire involve flammable and combustible liquids and gasses such as gasoline, alcohols, and propane",
      "choices": ["Class K", "Class A", "Class B", "Class D"],
      "answer": "Class B"
    }, 
    {
      "question": "_______ require special extinguishing agents that are usually produced for the specific metal.",
      "choices": ["Class K", "Class B", "Class A", "Class D"],
      "answer": "Class D"
    }, 
    {
      "question": "Dry chemicals used to interrupt the chemical chain reactions are also effective on ________ fires.",
      "choices": ["Class K", "Class B", "Class A", "Class D"],
      "answer": "Class A"
    },
    {
      "question": "______ fires most often occur where cooking media (fats, oils, and greases) are used, and most of the time are found in commercial cooking operations.",
      "choices": ["Class K", "Class B", "Class A", "Class D"],
      "answer": "Class K"
    }, 
    {
      "question": "Human survival, even for properly protected fire fighters, is difficult if not impossible for a few seconds within a compartment following a flashover for which stage of fire?",
      "choices": ["Incipient stage", "Free burning stage", "Both a and b", "None of the above"],
      "answer": "Free burning stage"
    }, 
    {
      "question": " Room temperatures can range from 1000–1500°F in:",
      "choices": ["Smoldering stage", "Free burning stage", "Both a and b", "None of the above"],
      "answer": "Smoldering stage"
    },
    {
      "question": "The objectives of U.S. The Department of Transportation labeling system standard are to",
      "choices": ["Provide an immediate warning of potential danger", "Inform emergency responders of the nature of the hazard", " State emergency spill or release control procedures", "All the above"],
      "answer": "All the above"
    }, 
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not flammable gas?",
      "choices": ["Ethene", "Methane", "Methyl chloride", "All the above"],
      "answer": "Ethene"
    }, 
    {
      "question": "The letter W with a bar through it indicates:",
      "choices": ["Use no water", "Avoid the use of water", "Use no steam", "Use oxidizer"],
      "answer": "Avoid the use of water"
    }, 
    {
      "question": "The NFPA 704 Diamond indicates:",
      "choices": ["Health", "Flammability", "Reactivity", "All of these"],
      "answer": "All of these"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the colours in NFPA 704 Diamond:",
      "choices": ["Blue, Orange, White, Red", "Blue, Purple, green, white", "Blue, red, yellow, white", "Purple, pink, red, green"],
      "answer": "Blue, red, yellow, white"
    }, 
    {
      "question": "What are the three elements of the fire triangle?",
      "choices": ["Heat, oxygen and fuel", "Heat, nitrogen and fuel", "light, oxygen and fuel", "Heat, oxygen and gas"],
      "answer": "Class K"
    }, 
    {
      "question": "This heat must be controlled and kept away from fuel unless carefully controlled.",
      "choices": ["True", "False", "Cannot Say", "Depends"],
      "answer": "True"
    }, 
    {
      "question": "Oxygen gas is used:",
      "choices": ["in welding", "in hyperbaric chambers as a medical treatment", "in steelworks and chemical plants", "All of the above"],
      "answer": "All of the above"
    }, 
    {
      "question": "The main causes of fires and explosions when using oxygen are:",
      "choices": ["oxygen enrichment from leaking equipment", "use of materials compatible with oxygen", "use of oxygen in equipment designed for oxygen service", "correct operation of oxygen equipment"],
      "answer": "Class K"
    },
    {
      "question": "Oxygen should be used to “sweeten” the air in a confined space",
      "choices": ["True", "False", "Cannot Say", "Depends"],
      "answer": "False"
    },
    {
      "question": "Flammable materials include:",
      "choices": ["flammable liquids (e.g. petrol)", "flammable gasses (e.g. propane and butane)", "flammable solids (e.g. charcoal, paper)", "All of the above"],
      "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
      "question": "Flammable liquids should not be decanted within the store",
      "choices": ["True", "False", "Cannot Say", "Depends"],
      "answer": "True"
    },
    {
      "question": "Equipment or components that radiate heat, such as kettles, catalytic converters and mufflers, cannot be ignition sources.",
      "choices": ["True", "False", "Cannot Say", "Depends"],
      "answer": "False"
    },
    {
      "question": "OSHA describes a hazardous atmosphere as:",
      "choices": ["one which is oxygen-deficient", "one which is oxygen-rich", "Both of the above", "None of the above"],
      "answer": "Both of the above"
    },
    {
      "question": "Class A of fire involves:",
      "choices": ["flammable gasses or liquids, such as propane", "vegetable or animal cooking oils or fats", "energized electrical components", "ordinary combustibles, such as paper, trash, some plastics."],
      "answer": "ordinary combustibles, such as paper, trash, some plastics."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these is not a part of the fire extinguisher?",
      "choices": ["Discharge lever", "Discharge hose", "Discharge nozzle", "Water panel"],
      "answer": "Water panel"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the easy acronym when using a fire extinguisher?",
      "choices": ["P.A.S.S", "P.I.S.S", "P.E.S.S", "P.O.S.S"],
      "answer": "P.A.S.S"
    },
    {
      "question": "The most common equipment in buildings to facilitate emergency evacuations are:",
      "choices": ["fire alarms", "exit signs", "emergency lights", "All of the above"],
      "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
      "question": "The urgent instant egress or escape of people away from a place containing an imminent threat, an ongoing threat, or a hazard to lives or property is referred to as emergency evacuation.",
      "choices": ["True", "False", "Cannot Say", "Depends"],
      "answer": "True"
    },
    {
      "question": "Class K of fire involves:",
      "choices": ["flammable gasses or liquids, such as propane", "vegetable or animal cooking oils or fats", "energized electrical components", "ordinary combustibles, such as paper, trash, some plastics"],
      "answer": "vegetable or animal cooking oils or fats"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following properties are of inert gas?",
      "choices": ["Resistant to chemical action", "Explodes if it is mixed with air", "Supports combustion", "Oxygen deficient"],
      "answer": "Resistant to chemical action"
    },
    {
      "question": "Leakage of any gas (except oxygen) inside a confined/enclosed space can not cause displacement of oxygen resulting in an oxygen deficient atmosphere.",
      "choices": ["True", "False", "Cannot Say", "Depends"],
      "answer": "False"
    },
    {
      "question": "Hazards while using gas cylinder is/are?",
      "choices": ["Oxygen deficient atmosphere resulting in asphyxiation.", "If the valve breaks, the sudden release of compressed gas didn’t turn it into a lethal projectile.", "Gas cylinders should not be capped.", "None of the above"],
      "answer": "Oxygen deficient atmosphere resulting in asphyxiation."
    },
    {
      "question": "Percentage of oxygen deficient in atmosphere is unsafe and not permitted.",
      "choices": ["Above 21%", "19.5%", "12 - 19.5", "Less than 6%"],
      "answer": "19.5%"
    },
    {
      "question": "An atmosphere having more than 21% of oxygen is considered as an oxygen enriched atmosphere and is safe for entry/working.",
      "choices": ["True", "False", "Cannot Say", "Depends"],
      "answer": "False"
    },
    {
      "question": "If the vapour air mixture is within the flammable range, it can explode in the presence of an ignition source.",
      "choices": ["True", "False", "Cannot Say", "Depends"],
      "answer": "True"
    },
    {
      "question": "TLV Stands for?",
      "choices": ["Type length value", "To value loan", "Threshold Limit Value", "None of the above"],
      "answer": "Threshold Limit Value"
    },
    {
      "question": "What one should not do while receiving gas cylinders",
      "choices": ["Properly labeled", "Accept cylinders without label", "Check Damage", "Cylinders have valve caps"],
      "answer": "Accept cylinders without label"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following needs to be checked while storing gas cylinders inside labs",
      "choices": ["Gas cylinders should use immediately", "Cylinders can place near heat sources", "Materials can store above cylinders", "All of the above"],
      "answer": "Gas cylinders should use immediately"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is false regarding safe use of gas cylinders?",
      "choices": ["Do not tamper with cylinders", "Use correct regulator for cylinder", "Use damaged pipes, regulators", "Ensure proper ventilation"],
      "answer": "Use damaged pipes, regulators"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is/are correct emergency measures",
      "choices": ["Protective equipments should be used", "Gas supplier may not be intimated", "Personal protective equipment should not be used while dealing with gas leaks", "All of the above"],
      "answer": "Protective equipments should be used"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the pressure above which cylinder should be operated?",
      "choices": ["15 psi", "10 psi", "25 psi", "35 psi"],
      "answer": "25 psi"
    },
    {
      "question": "When should we close the cylinder valve?",
      "choices": ["Work in progress", "Work is completed", "Cylinder is filled", "Before work"],
      "answer": "Work is completed"
    },
    {
      "question": "Where should we store toxic gases?",
      "choices": ["Inside Vessel", "Gas Cabinet", "On gas cylinder", "Near flame"],
      "answer": "Gas Cabinet"
    },
    {
      "question": "Where should we store toxic gases?",
      "choices": ["Inside Vessel", "Gas Cabinet", "On gas cylinder", "Near flame"],
      "answer": "Gas Cabinet"
    }
  ]
}